

44 Oakland Ave. - Moncton/NB

□ (506) 588-9289 | 
■ fstoaldo@gmail.com | 
□ fstoaldo

## Summary\_

Analytical and pragmatic professional who aims to automate and improve the agility of any given task. Recognized for giving creative ideas to solve daily problems as well as to delivering accurate reports and results. Worked on both the technical and commercial sides of businesses for well-known multinational companies.

## Skills

**Programming** Python and Java **Front-end** HTML5 and CSS

**Languages** Bilingual in English and Portuguese

**Others** Problem solving, troubleshooting, post-sales support, following-up

## Education

Network Administration Moncton/NB

NBCC

2020

• Powershell, Linux, Cisco IOS, and Microsoft Windows Server, SQL, and Exchange

#### **Bachelor of Electrical Engineering**

Brazil

FEI (UNIVERSITY CENTER OF FEI)

2012

2019

• Capstone project awarded as one of the best of the year

# Professional Development \_\_\_\_\_

#### **Object Oriented Programming in Java (Specialization)**

UCSD / Duke - Coursera 2020

- OOP design: inheritance, polymorphism, method overloading and overriding
- Performance analysis of different algorithms on large data sets
- Test units using JUnit in Eclipse

#### **Algorithms and Data Structures: Design and Analysis**

STANFORD - LAGUNITA

Implementation and asymptotic analysis of algorithms

- Implementation and asymptotic analysis of algorithms
- · Divide and conquer, sorting and searching, shortest paths, heaps, trees, hash tables, greedy algorithms, and dynamic programming
- Algorithms implemented in Python

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

TECHNICAL SALESMAN

Mersen Brazil

• Responsible for the sales of custom machined graphite tools and pieces.

2017 - 2018

- Worked directly with the Sales Manager, providing technical and commercial support off-site to clients and sales representatives as well
  as follow-ups.
- · Improved the price calculation process in order to delivery formal quotations faster and more accurately.

**Huawei** Brazil

CONFIGURATION ENGINEER 2015 - 2016

• Technical sales and support for the main ISPs of Brazil, dealing with backbone equipment for the DWDM, SDH, and Microwave networks.

- Design and pricing of large-scale projects country-wide as well as reporting KPIs to the administrative staff.
- Recognized for automating the SLA (Service Level Agreement) weekly report. This automation reduced the time spent to generate the report from 4 days to 1 hour.

AES / Votorantim Brazil

ANALYST 2013 - 2014

- Responsible for the commercial support for the issues related to the distribution of electrical energy to enterprise customers in the Sao Paulo State.
- Improved reports regarding frequency and duration of outages.
- · Analysed data to define best approaches to tackle customers' defaults, and utilisation of the power-grid infra-structure.

E**ricsson** Brazil

ADVANCED ENGINEERING INTERN

2010 - 2012

• Provided the interface between ISPs and the factory plant as well as equipment dimensioning (for 3G and 2G plants) via site surveys and blueprints reading.

## **Extracurricular Activity**

2010 **Workshop** - Wireless Embedded Applications - Motorola/FEI

Brazil

2008 Volunteer Work - Lar de Maria Daycare

Brazil

## Interests\_

**Professional** Software development, convergence of AI and automation, IoT

**Personal** Reading and photography